Welcome to build a hi there I'm
...there I am the software...a
...software engineering manager here at microsoft working on the visual
studio id team getting this talk on writing visual studio
extensions I'm going to sort of give you an overview of how to get started some tips
antics along the way and by the end of the talk I hope that you'll have enough under your
belt to go back and start building extensions for visual studio ...
The agenda for this talk is I'm going to start with a vary basic
a extension and, walk you through the process of understanding what goes
into extension then we'll go about publishing extension and as we goal
down the road...different aspects of visions...extensibility fundamentals like math
...packages and whatnot and
the towards the end we'll put it all together to sort of get a sense of what we have accomplished and what
more you could actually accomplish in terms of building extensions...studio?
...to the asset is very powerful and extensible there's tons of functionality
...visual studio comes with so,
much...that sometimes I wonder where that...too much in there and,
what would you do but then I just step back and say what would you do if you...some of the functionality
does not even exist that, for example, if I had a swiss army knife and, I needed to use
...to start the flame or hammer to break all something like that right may not missing some
function because obviously cannot use ...me knife to break a while so,
that's the sort of...make within...when we build a feature
...functionality we look at it and say is this something thatextension author can...if an
...author can extended then probably will think a little bit more before we add that functionality
...years but at times we are also realize that some function to cannot be added by
an extension author at all right then we go about adding the function
...so there's a reason why there's tons of functionality in...there's a method to the magnus right
...visual studio given that it has so much functionality in there it's completely configure...like a
lot of things that can...for example, in this case I'm using the?
Light team if I wanted to change the team for visual studio
...go about and say.
Such for team in the quick lunch ...there and then that puts
...tools options window and then right now I'm using blue I could go change it to
...team and well-off.
I'm using that came now for the purpose of this demo I'm going to continue usinglight
team because it's sort of sits well with the rest of the slide deck I'm going to use the blue thing that.
So, visual...like this is just an example of how configured able visual studio...but,
then there is a reason why it's still extensible well,
there's lots of...configured able that might still be places waiting ...
you might realize that whatever comes in the...standard configuration option might not be good enough for you and,
you could change a...studio behavior for that are using cord
...xml file...of the back let's jump into our
first demo it's if it's going to be very simple bsix project.
For that what I'm going to do is I'm going to do a
...project pulls in.
The new project dialogue box and,...there I have I'm on the extensibility not I'm
...mean this extensibility not x exists right now because ahead
...for the demo purposes and I select the basics project now I'm talking
vsix but ortiz we six basics is a file that gets generated from a
...project that's what we're doing right now the vsix file
...unit of deployment for visual studio extension visual studio
...extension and, install the contents of the file to
the right location vsix file is...zip file and,
that uses open packaging...and...can rename that art basics extension
to dot zip and you can see the contents of the zip file basically I'm using any zip
...like windows file explorer even if you ask me what we six
...well I would say it's real studio installer for extensions.
So, now going back to...project that just got...you see that it doesn't have any
...at all and it just has a bsix manifest and the
...right now in the manifest design...there are a few feeds in
here that I'd like to take some time to walk you through.
The first one is the product name this is what shows up...someone installs this
extension rate when you go into extensions...sell-out box names that you
...here these are the extensions that are installed for me the names in here
...pick from the product name that are specified by that specific extension author
from the author name by default gets put in from the
...information that they used design individual studio the product
...by default combination of product name and author name and denigrate you can also
...will also have to specify...venue update your of extension and uploaded together
you'll keep changing the version number so that your customers who are using your vsix get updated
russians there are there is a description and what not you can also provide
license has well it's in the form of...
So, forext I'm going to.
Provide.
License file.
And, then now let's look at install targets and what that means so,
...targets here what it's saying is this
basics installs on fourteen dot
...all russian of visual studio targets...of...which is basically visual studio
...and, then it also says that...targets pro?
...us look at all the other plausible options of the product identifier a bunch of options in here
...what do each of these mean before we understand what each of these
mean we'll have to take a small...art to understand the visual studious q model basically
...model he's...channel model integrated shell is the smallest
...in there it's the and, what ships with visual student
...is the integrated development environment
...and source control integration it does not have any programming language
included with it and,
this is usually used by extend as...to sort of at their
own programming language and have their own custom visual studio an environment so,
if you...to build and extension that targets integrated...then
...extension would be install not only on the...visuals
...skills by a by all the other extend those who might have build their own
...using integrated...rate and on top of visual studio
...integrated shel you have express...and,
the community skew express q does not have third-party extensibility support
community skew is a free...visual studio that
does have support for extensibility the excuse effort specific targeted scenarios like web
development windows desktop application development the pros and enterprise
...at page skills that are on top of community skew?
So, now if you were to have you extension target community what that means is...extension would instagram
...professional enterprise skews if you said
...just targets pro then it will install...pro enterprise basically it won't
install and community so,...overview...
letters jump onto dependencies you can specify dependencies for extension as well by
default what your vsix manifest is seeing here is a requires
...forgot...or higher you can add neuron?
Dependency as well and you could say I want to specify dependency from something that's already
installed on this machine and you could probably pick something like well.
How about?
...and, what you're seeing here is well as long as accord analysis
extension questions from fourteen dot org fifteen dot all basically fifteen
...fifteen...installed...this extension would not install anything which is what
...or higher basically measure version of...article and then this
...this extension...should be...that specify that?
And, now.
The other piece that I wanted to sort of touch upon is with the
install targets going back and start targets...something that I wanted upon that I did not
color these to check boxes...by default a vsix in...
for just the user...initiating...this...if however
you want to the vsix to be installed by all the users that use the machine then you
would check this box rate this is mostly used by extensions that
install a lot of productivity features have machine
wide licensing associated with them and use this typically have paid some
sizable amount of money to buy those features and expect this features to be...begins to
...and be available to all the users that use the machine basically and,
there is this another ...here which essentiallyis used
in a different sort of a scenario basically ...basics basically packages
...started...installer when you install visual studio it registers basis
...as the default installer for...bsix fights that the user
...bsix...then that's what the basics...launch and that's the one that extract the
package does have been location and...up so that visual studio consumes and
set faces the functionality that's provided in the vsix package?
when your...in certain situations you might want to actually like if
...an extension author who has functionality which
is not just contained within the basics,
for example,...writing a satirist which monitors the changes that the...making
...cord and it's probably...windows...maybe that gets and start and,
basics cannot ...cannot install anything outside of certain fold-out so,
what you would do then is...would packages vsix into them as...package that not only...as
the install of the...but also actually does this additional installation logic and then you might
...install...windows installer so that it doesn't get
set phased into the extensions updates dialogue box or something that can be...started so,
now with that sort of overview let us go about?
And, build the solution.
And, you'll see that...end...generating...basics package.
And, then what we'll do is?
...package and what's inside of it.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to?
Go to the location I'm going to rename.
And, then we can go look at.
The basics package and its contents great you can see that the license files included than there is the
...basics manifests included to be able to install this guy I'm going-to.
Dynamic back.
And, I'm going to...double-click.
Gained.
I can also view the log.
They log obviously tells me that the...this guy references stick
...analysis ext and,
also that this k and...package header dependence undercut framework
...pro and all that details that we
...the vsix and also it says that it was...to this location which happens to be
...so what...what I'm going to do now is I'm going to navigate to that location?
And, then we'll see that it just ...the contents of the vsix which was the manifest
...that's about it all right that's all goodness.
Now what we now you might be wandering validated like how did we decide how to the
basics installer dissect install to this location...so that's something that once again
you specified in a package defied we'll talk about...files in a minute but,
let's go look at a packed the package defy
let-me referring to here it's in visual studio
fourteen-hour common seven id the package...I'm talking about his dependent?
...and,...specifically data the few things that I want you to make
note of the...extensions that are installed for all...
The location that highlighted here this route for that happens to be program files
...know...version of visual studio basically common so ninety extensions and,
the...use extension score two local...data location
...the local...microsoft visual studio fourteen all
...extensions location and then the...
or this is another thing that also is interesting for you to keep in mind this is
...software microsoft visual studio fourteen that's where all...configure.
And, extension information and lot...information specific to...studious
store disappointing...input in order...the...spared...
They just information specific to that instance of...stowed...so that's also
once something that's big...from devon because...deaf so now.
Let's go back in here.
Let's start visual studio to actually see the extension sharp.
Although it doesn't do anything meaningful we can still...it listed in extensions updates
dialogue box the reason why I had to restart video studio
...because the extension was actually in started out of product and we maintain a
...basically right and, the cash doesn't get refreshed so we had to
restart bs for that reason you can see that the ext it was
...in fact let me go ahead and install extension because they want to.
Do something else as well which
is to actually goal publish ...gallery?
I was already signing together recite just...to show you the complete walk group so you can go
assigningusing.
And, then you can upload and extension.
in...at the point of this workplace to sort of give you an idea of how simple it
is for you to upload and extension once you have it so,
you picked and I just gave the extension that we just built it's pretty much
...dummy extension does nothing much I hope you don't upload them extensions
...extensions which...meaningful functionality and,
I'm going to delayed this extension right after that amos I'm going to give
it some description which is not probably very meaningful here but,
the reason why I'm giving this is so that you sort of.
See the process here so.
So, it's going about saving it's not published yet I'm going...publish.
And, then lights published let me...check.
If it's actually published from...
I'm going-to go-to online tag deception for the extensions
illegality maybe able just use vsix as my.
Sets trying to find it.
And, sure, enough it's there.
It's something that high created obviously this now
...fine I'll downloaded and yet I get my
extension and.
The you...
Right and, it...fine and, it shows upshared...effort shows up...list as...
I'm going down install it so now.
The now...get back to.
Slide to sort of wrap-up
of the fast tiny little demo here so,
what we ...so, far ...is we talk about what's in the
vsix package manifest we did the publishing what we did not do is
actually talk about the debugging and experimental instance select me?
The same project and then we look at.
Debugging specifically.
So, let's look at.
Debug properties for this project.
So, shared enough ...is the action when you had debug is to
...external program apparently okay and,
then it says run devon dot...well that's visual studio so it says just...to your to
run my extension project makes sense because you want extent extension
...within visual studio cone because...that makes sense the next thing is area
there's a command line argument as well that supplied which happens to be
...exp what this says is experimental instances where this thing so
what's experimental instance let's sort of take a moment to understand that and why that even
exist?
...experimental instance official studio is...you basically to...a different registry...case when
we are looking at the if you remember we were looking at the...
Hi, earlier so, the experimental instance has its own...and,
the point of the this isolation not only does it have a
high of its own the extensions also get installed
...different location from the standard instance of
visual studio the point of this isolation is so that you are development environment
...is distinctly separate from your debug environment so that if you
had any extensions which are developing which are not good enough then that doesn't pollute...
development environment and sort of getting to bad situations the other piece that you want also
not make not...is all the extensions that...debugging and
within the same experimental instance if you what building ten different extensions and,
then all ten of them will showing this same experimental instance in itself so,
with that let's actually see.
How the debug experience...actually looks like so let's start debugging?
And, then...stacked...we...studio experimental instance if we could studio.
Not only does it start experimental instead
...instance...studio it also goes about it...make sure that this experimental instance
...studio has your extension installed so the one thing that you'll see is
that title has experimental instance in here
...regular visual studio obviously does not have that in the title and,
then if you went and looked at extensions and updates you will see vsix project one.
In here which was not the case.
For the standard instance let's close this guy and, go back to slide deck
and sort of summarize what recovered so far right so we covered these expected
manifests what goes...package how easy and simply...for
you to publisher package we also looked at the experimental instance and
how that works as well the one little tidbit that might also
be useful eventually he is looking at what happens the specific thing that
have one of the specific things that happens when yet building
...project which is for that will have to look at
b cs project associated?
For this project and, then the fun thing that I wanted to talk about is the
...targets so, you extensibility project
inputs the...decay targets now.
What does the targets well actually contain let's
scope look up the targets file to get a sense of what's in there?
So, the target file has a bunch of tasks if you're
...as build architecture you probably understand what tasks do I'm not going to get into the details of him
as build architecture and what not here what?
Are the tasks...has done is a defines a bunch of tasks and,
you'll notice that as part of building
...basics project yep get stepped up the manifest gets validated and,
the ext gets and installed and started back so it it's some useful source of information for
you to go look at and if you're finding something that's unique...project
build process then probably this is a place for you to start looking at?
So, with that what I'm going to do it now is sort of
switch gears and actually start adding some meaningful functionality to our project?
So, what we'll do is real go about?
And, new item.
And, then what we're going to do is add and extensibility item and
...data margin so what does this do basically this template like
...is described here it creates a bit...editor margin that pleases?
Green box across the bottom of...viewpoint so,
that's what this get as so.
Let's go about.
Adding.
Data...and, you'll see that the template ended up adding a bunch of
references.
Mostly do input...interfaces and start using interfaces that exposed by
...and, then it added a couple of classes in here slated margin one
...ts has constructor what the constructor does is basically it
...label?
Which...a background as light-green and that's a text
to it okay now going to their...margin
...factory cs it has?
A method
...which creates a margin the most interesting piece with this.
Class...actually the fact that it has a
bunch of attributes in here and that's what I think is most interesting for me in
...and the one of the attributes here is the expert attribute ...get a sense of what
these attributes mean and what not will have to look at math the managed extensibility framework but,
before that let us just go about build this project?
Run it to see the sort of functionality that it.
Okay, so, we...experimental instance.
And, just going to create a simple console application.
So, that we have...file.
And, then we can look at the editor margin once we open the client.
Right so you see there it's functional yes it does something by adding...
margin has some text here and then has...background for products
let's close this guy and then start talking about what is
...so murphy's managed extensibility framework enables
you to build extensible applications within extending that application would be as
simple as dropping a bunch of binary store location and then
...studio just pick up the binary is and then include it and,
surface the functionality that you extension implements into yes basically right
so that's sort of the capability that powerful capability of extensibility that nef provides?
Right and this managed extensibility framework actually ships with dot net framework and you'll need system
dot co model namespaces
where functionality for murphy's actually surfaced so let's sort of walk through
a typical extensibility scenario rate in here we have an application and a couple of
...extension and extension be extension...has a tool window
...application could say well I need to windows extension be has a menu and,
it's as I got a menu and then application could...I need menus and
...consuming those menus in addition to that not only do these extensions actress have
...the functionality they probably will also need some functionality like extension a might
say I need a many accessories and application could say...got
...service havel and gifts that...service back to extension and extension was about
using that and for all practical purposes maybe some of the functionality of
...semis isresult of the helped extension be provided by actually implementing a
mania right similarly extension be could say I need a tool windows sideways and than
the application...article windows...use it.
So, that's sort of the model where in the extensions actually use some functionality within
the application and they also provide some functionality to the application so,
to sort of get these concepts little bit more concrete understanding of this concepts
let's start looking at a demo project that they have.
Ok, so, this demo project basically.
The...does something similar to what we talked on the
slide deck right it has defined a bunch of interfaces at
tooling the interface menu interface and then it also defines the menu service
encoding the service right and, then the?
Program cs essentially has.
A class some...window which implements the
tool window interface the application which keeps track of all the.
Right and,
then a provide something to query the window.
Given a name and then there is a menu...which implements their
...surveys and then eventually data is this main method which sort of
hooks up the...window the application menu service together
...of seeing the application keeps track of all the cool windows
today and menus...window get some...your service in this manner and,
that's that and then this is essentially to sort of pool
...now everything's hooked up...so let us around this.
...app is a
...that got created and then there's a menu...is that created okay fine.
But, now let is until
...situation here that now if some how you...is
...another...winter than what would you do you would go about saying well?
Tool winter tool.
Thank is what we do and then you start listing that...winter too?
In here.
So, lot-of ugliness here advances start extending because now you have to not only do add this
additional functionality but also actually have...changer application
core to accomplish that now all fine if you controlled all of your
...maybe that's still find recompile is fine but how about if you
wanted your application to be extensible they'd then you would what would you do in the case
within some extension author that wants to hook up to you and provide...little window
...you have good bit invent...extensibility mechanism on how the application
...that registers...windows invade usually those
tool windows from that and that's sort of the problem that basically...of
try to solve and solve in a very elegant manner using reflection
and dot net reflection and whatnot so to see all of...action let's go about?
Using methane that example
...this sort of give you an overview of how simple that actually ends up looking.
...so, had...to the component model composition
...and then I'll...add a few using.
And, then...also use.
Deflection as well eventually so we added a few using
...pull in a few types whereas.
And, then I'm going to say the some...window basically
...cycle window so how do I.
Specify that they saying export.
...if I did not specify type of ical window then by...could end up
exporting some tool window the class but that's not what I want.
You want...the interface.
And, then the class out also actually.
Needs menu service.
So, I'm going to say I need that type of.
...service.
Right so that
math now knows that okay this is another dependency that needs to be satisfied.
The application.
Many tool windows not just one so.
...have built.
Do then is used input many attribute and see that...
Any...windows.
Okay.
And, then.
Many service obviously.
Thank box.
I'm reading service.
And, then it can ports many menus.
...in then so we have added a few exports and imports to sort of declarative
...specify dependencies what I'm going to do is I'm going to.
The more all of the composition
homemade composition and actually start using
...aps stoke.
Compose.
I'm going to start off by creating.
Catalog.
And, that catalog is an assembly catalog ...from types that...
The executing assembly.
Current...only thing.
That kind of something that building.
And, then I'm going to create a container.
And, then I'm going to compose a parts for the...and,
then let's see if we can resolve this complet as well.
...on key there and that's okay.
Application obviously has a.
Get...so I'm going to get...using the name.
...days what they specified as the name.
Thank.
You hit some ideas that.
...stack so now let as a sort of take a moment to sort of understand
what's going on here in these field lines of code that.
...building the...the assembly catalog classing here is doing is
it's going about enumerating all the types methods fields that has
...input...defined on it and then create a collection of composer
...that's a compose able part it's a compressible unit in
...basically rate in other words like a compressible park holds information regarding either
an input of an expert unit and then...composition container on the
catalog what happened was the completion container gets the exports from the
And, then the exports imap the inputs once we do the compose part.
So, that's the matchmaking process essentially happens when...the...parts...all the dependencies
as satisfied well the succeeds basically right and then we now have access to the
...window as well ...of also look at
...fun thing with...let's.
Go about enumerating all the parts.
So, what we're going...do is?
...going to look at all expert definitions and then we're going to just paint.
All the all of them.
Okay,...was a...failures say probably missed something.
Until window doesn't hem...means said...
So, for now let...this out we can get to innovate.
The point that I wanted to show was actually a cool wind itself.
Can be access I mean we can access...windows from the application which is the case
And, we were able to enumerate the exports as well
...purposes I'm going to keep rolling but,...with our current talk so,
If you remember we talked about the extension needing a menu
service and application saying that well I got a menu service
well that translates to sort of import-export from
...terminology that everything is a pocket from a wealth...standpoint
...extensions that...parts and your applications and is a...everything is apart
Now let's take a moment to talk about what we have covered so
...with regards to...when we're dealing with nef we need to understand that parts expert
something...then there is a composition that puts it all together
to accomplish that dairies catalog that keeps track of all the providers of
functionality there is a container that plays the role of matchmaking by finding exports
and...and, satisfies the inputs we looked at that somebody catalog in this example
...as well like the...catalog which is sort of what gets use when you want to
...your extensions...directly location then you basically have a direct catalog and,
the...gets built based on all the
...assemblies that in that specific directly that you're looking at it also that
advanced concepts like lazy inputs and, specifying metadata
on...as well that have not covered thosefor your on study at some point of
...but the point for me here was to actually give you an overview of...
why does visual studio use ...to make its own extensibility ...simple
bankrupting extension not that's create partition and modular pieces of functionality has
we have seen miffed brings that the ability to compose functionality easily
ending creators designing and implementing completely de-couple pieces of software?
Which is ideal from and extensibility standpoint these design patents make it possible to create maintain able
software in the long-run so now let's go back to our editor margin example?
Switch over to that and, then start looking at the.
Attributes
...specific attributes right in here what we're saying is ...
Is that it saying that well this classic sports the aida
...text...margin provide at night and,
then the editor obviously inputs all the?
All the entities all the parts that sdp is specify
...margin toyed it and then what it does based on that
is then it goes about creating margin on those...and that happens
...today extension actually got the opportunity to had the background
and text thank and,
also there was another attribute a few attributes that are of interest here that data
case about the specify that this is a...this is applicable for...content type
...also specified that this is applicable...for the bottom marginally
okay and, we also gave it a name as well up here?
That's that additional...provided now.
So, I wanted also...a couple of things that are specific to
...studios usage...
So, what
visual studio does is a venue user basics package to install extension
...basics instead of comes along installs the package to the extensions for...basically
...extensions for that...and, then when
...sets it up so that on subsequently start because to...understands that and...and start and,
then visual studio will go about scanning extensions for that and when it does that it obviously
...calls the compose parts to build a...and after that what it also
does it make sure that it updates its on cache of extensions and them...cash that it
...that keeps the point of the cash is so that it doesn't scanned extensions for
...all the time on a restart...does that only when
an extension was installed previously?
So, that's sort of something that needs sort of unique to how visual studio manages
miffed based extensions.
So, now switching gas we're going to look at visual studio packages and how networks
...start to get started what we'll do is...add a menu item and commanded gets executed
when the usertaxonomy item in the process I hope to provide you an overview of
...extensibility concepts like package...package registration command routing
that will help you when you look at creating abs package yourself at a
high-level bs package is a means
for extension author to provide common extensibility objects in a container that is
deployed and licensed as a single entity basically functionality surface
...package can be used by other objects in the
...package or in another package in terms of types of things that you could do you could write your
...salaries and, you would provide that envious package you
...as could previous packages visual studios editor itself is
...package in project systems audio elements like manual and,
tool windows those called so would be in bs packages...so without
let us transition to a simple demo variable...in your comment?
Some back to add demo project that we've been using so far we are going to continue
an...new extensibility item.
And, we're going to add a custom command.
And, we'll see that ...a bunch of
...that can be added and a few files that will be added as a result of this so,
the differences that added here you'll see that data...immutable and
...interrupt somebody that added we need those for some coding
...types for shel interfaces structures and classes and
photo packaged registration attributes now let's look at
thesource code that was added as a result of this so let's look at command
when packaged cs.
Thing.
You'll see that it has a few attributes.
And, then the package itself inhibits from.
Microsoft visual studio...package...
And, you'll notice that there is a...here in the constructed so,
that's something of but, making not off so, what we what it's
saying here...tells us that we can...initialization what sort of initialization
...can going here and what cannot and it says that it
talks about something called package...date so,
what...sedate?
And, what is package...mean that's something that we
would I would want to take a moment to talk about then we develop a package it is modular unit
...functionality right ...it is loaded...studio it becomes part of visual
...itself so, what does that mean well, if
you're developing something which is module of its own like...and regular some
...that gets loaded by a regular application then?
The application just uses the functionality that's provided by the
ideal of it's unlikely that the dl use
...some of the functionality that's in the application that's the distinction between
...package and the regular modules in when you build
...package not only does vs use the functionality that surfaced by that
we as package between as packaging itself also starts
has the ability to consume and use the functionality that these envious
and also from other...packages as well so what?
Package...does here essentially is that
then the packages after the packages...essentially becomes part of
...pretty before...is a sighted that does not happen so, for the package to be
...you should actually have implemented the ideas package interface that's
something that we get for free here because we just inherited from the package class.
...studio eventually...as per initialize as well after the packages
...so at this point we can actually
...method is called we can actually start using some of this at
...that...part of visual studio so let's go take a look at the
command one initialize because that's what gets card.
Not initialize method for come bs becoming
...package essentially...will see that the constructor
...card and the constructive actually users...so, yeah,
...able to actually axis medius from within...package some of the
services colombia's and the what it does here is pretty minimal
rate what it does is it adds the command and the come
...essentially a command ad...even handler and,
then it adds that to the comment...so that no...service...when I use
...a specific command call this even-handed basically so,
that's what has happened so now let as.
Look, at another piece of information they by going back to the.
...when package.
...here we looked at this packaged registration...what this what this
...registration attribute does is it what it
is singing here is that...the resources for this the ll are not in settler...cities in the same
...data things that you can specify using the packages
...registration attribute things like that this
package can be loaded in the background in a different tradeoff not the
install product registration attribute basically...that provide information so that it shows
...help about dialogue box the other useful one for you to sort of noise
provide menu resource what this case says is well the menu resources?
That are built from the...city file now what is obviously fell we'll get to that in a minute that
...from...city file should be in a mode in...resource named menus
dirty menu and here's the version of the...the point of versioning
their resources essentially for the...studio caching so that we should studio
...means performant and doesn't have to look up
the resources all the time every...loaded but,
only when actually the version changes?
Right so that's goodness from a performance standpoint so now going to
the via cp file.
Itself what is the city file well it's a
...table and, what's in what's in it.
...let's start by looking at line-by-line sort of there is this
...dot h and what does that file actually have it has
a command id ...all the menus in ...commands so,
that's defined in dead-end for if you were interested in looking up at all the
...information that's the header...for you to go look
Other important elemental you to pay attention to is sort of the
commands.
The node the commands that associated with the package
...package identified uniquely by a good
...and that's what specified here and that good is defined.
In the symbol section.
Right so that's what.
Identifies the comments and then the
commands element in itself has obviously if your children in here.
Most notably three groups buttons and...great
...element is used to group related command groups
...not case we have only one command...and then each group is tighter
...menu group and then what we're saying is spell I'm adding a new group on the cools manual
okay that's what this is defining and you have the buttons
the element...the buttons element you can specify the buttons and,
you try a button group?
...command eighty and then you see that this is part of this
...group.
And, you also specify...which is a bitmap in this case.
Okay, so, now that...sort of lebed the.
Overall high-level taxonomy off the cp file it as
Demo...sort of...what going on.
Okay, so, we have.
Added.
Menu command obviously and then it does something which is just through the
dialogue box in there.
So, that's all this...so now let is go back to
...sort of look at.
What happened behind-the-scenes in terms of building this package basically so,
we start off with the resource files the rest xfiles bs package
...and resources gutless x and, those are those are basically process...as jan
...the to create the dot resource files then the dot me a city file that we looked at
...processed by...is the command table compiler and then...generates a dot
And, then that dot seo
...added to the bs package dot resource file and the name of that
resources work be specified in here.
And, it also has a question that we specified in here right and then.
The resource file and the source...are processed by the csharp compiler to generate that
The assembly file is then processed by the create package difficult...to generate
...package...in our case.
We can.
Look, at the package...file that god created.
So,...what it has is it has the package grid that we looked at it has the.
The ll which contains the functionality it also has information on the menu
...is located and that sort of what stuff so this is what get
...and separating in determining whether it needs to rebuild its manual cash have...
And, then the package the file and,...files that were generated out processed by the
...tasks.
And, then to generate the basics package.
...let as a switch to a simple to dwindle...how easy it is for you to create a
...as well.
And, in the process I'll also try to demo how you could change the
state of your commands as well right so it...window and then I am
looking at the even handler for that will...I'm going to hack up some thing?
But, a sort of moving this menu command.
To be at class.
To...to be the to be a member of this class.
So, that...can access directly.
Not that great solution but, sort of.
Something to sort of demo what I'm trying to accomplish here.
So, I'm going to say.
I'm going to keep coddling.
I'm going to keep targeting the.
...the other...that we also need to do to be able to accomplish that
he's to change and add command flag.
To say that this is this ...needs dynamic visibility so that you can change
All right so, we did that and then I'm going to...
And, then the cool window was actually.
Added we didn't get to that...can here.
Many itemize...sort of getting the to
...right and then you can see that the new
...is visible in here I'm going to.
Make it invisible.
Thank you visible okay.
So, we detach pretty simple...window you can add...as well but I want
to sort of take a moment to talk about basic command handling concepts here.
...what's a command, command is a logical entity that represents an action that a
...to perform it is backed by code to accomplish
the action button is ui invoke the command.
Context is something that represents the state of environment we have not leverage to that yet in
a demos for instance
...commands that enabled only in certain contexts will look at context
in a moment an example is a step into is
...your debugging right state will get the visibility state there are
other states like enable disabled so command can habits on state basic and
then command target he is an entity that knows how to execute...status query
...action associated with the command the...target could execute
action could projected of routed to another target?
And, finally the action is the code that is executed by a command target pena
...days executed on it.
So,...let us look, at contexts a little bit so what we're going to
do is one final demo vision before...wrapping things up.
So, what we're going to do here he is?
I'm going to add.
Visibility constraint.
On visibility...
Great.
Pain that I'm going to specify.
Command and that's a combination of the...and then the I.
And, then I'm going to specify in what context...going to be visible.
Okay, and, what I'm going to do also is...
This so that it starch direct so that ...to...that it needs to.
Updates menus.
So, what we did there was we said that this is this menu should be visible only
...there is no solution?
Noted and if there is a solution loaded...don't trick...solution loaded search
...this thing up selects load up a solution and see if that works and if
...basically...tools...
Ok, solutions loaded.
Not there anymore.
So, we saw how context is also functional now.
So, from command visibility...different things you...we just looked at the not solution you could also to the
...make it visible on given that is empty solution,
solution exists a bunch of things that you could do in here in terms of a visibility setting the
visibility like if...make sure that this command is available only when you're running in full-screen more,
for example.
...back what we have done so far is we looked at prefix
we looked at the basics manifest and how the sixes actually installed and whatnot places to look
at...you encountering issues between six...mat-file how to leverage it and build
...based extensions we looked bs packages and,
the oral architecture...package what this packet
...means we also looked at the manuals and commands how
to associate them we also them and we just used a few extensions like
...just a simple edit and...based extensions then we uploaded
extension...extension to gallery and sort of said how easy it is for you to
upload your extensions to gallery what more can you extend you can do a whole lot of things
like project templates can be customize the extent...extensible code snippets you can
...unquote snippets refactoring can be done debugged realize
...encoding standards and policy enforce new language satirist modeling tool solution
...tons of things that are extensible in here and you can go do that
this was just getting started and tips and tricks for-you to get
...a few assessing here...decays the place for you to start and,
communication is a free version of visual studio which is pretty much on...with...
studio professional so that's the place where you start if you're building extensions and some
resources on math as well for you to go look at I hope you enjoyed the talk and,
happy extension building...thank you?